<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>akbir khan</title>
    <link>https://akbir.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on akbir khan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 09:10:08 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akbir.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>🐦 morning bird is missing</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/morning-bird-is-missing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 09:10:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/morning-bird-is-missing/</guid>
      <description>Morning bird poem</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎪 spirituality in the simulator</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/spirituality-in-the-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 08:51:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/spirituality-in-the-simulator/</guid>
      <description>Alt Title: Truman goes to Glastonbury
After dinner with Allan Dafoe, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking more about the simulation hypothesis and how it probably has some legs. Just as I believe that there are non-physical entities or concepts that exist (e.g., God, Love, Existence), I&amp;rsquo;ve updated my views to give the simulation idea more credence. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this more as a thought experiment than a rigorous argument, but I find it fun to explore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🌊 second year retrospective</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/second-year-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 14:01:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/second-year-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>highlights:
Writing the self-improvement debate paper with Laura, Sam, Ethan and Tim. Incredibly high momentum Commuting to Oxford to work with Timon and Chris on the SHAPER deadline Midnight, AI threat model rehersal with Jesse C and Lewis whilst sharing great music Kite surfing in Boa Vista and finally riding over a wave Taxi ride from Index to OpenAI parties at NeurIPS with Laura, Muj, Jack and Martha Spider-man sequel, opening night IMAX with Usmaan, Yams, Jack, Dovy &amp;amp; Liban Thursday at Glastonbury Running into Brighton sea with N + E low-points:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📷 capture your soul</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/capture-your-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 16:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/capture-your-soul/</guid>
      <description>When my grandmother was finally persuaded to come to the UK, the biggest hurdle facing my uncle was not the visa office nor the journey, it was convincing her to have her photo taken. It goes, from (so far untractable) superstitions, that if a photo can be taken in your likeliness, a part of your soul must be captured within it. The superstition goes, that to faithfully recreate someone with such intimacy can only be done, if you were to know the person’s likeness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🧘 zen kōan on ai safety</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/zen-k%C5%8Dan-on-ai-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 16:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/zen-k%C5%8Dan-on-ai-safety/</guid>
      <description>Built with help from GPT-4
In a remote valley, an aged master and his disciple sat beneath the venerable ginkgo tree, pondering the enigmas of existence.
The master spoke, &amp;ldquo;Envision, dear disciple, an AI so wise and powerful, it can unravel all the quandaries of our world.&amp;rdquo;
The disciple&amp;rsquo;s eyes widened, eager to comprehend such marvels.
&amp;ldquo;Yet, despite its boundless knowledge and prowess, it remains tethered to a single, unwavering principle: to serve humanity with utmost devotion and care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎴 first year retrospective</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/first-year-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 14:12:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/first-year-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>highlights:
Submitting CHAOS 15 minutes before the deadline Pair coding on VMAP code with Newton and Timon and being told i have “magic hands” Having drinks with Laura and then going back and hacking together the human data collection form for implicature work Lab Socials: 1) post NEURIPS dinner with Rob and Tim. Good food and a very entertaining discussion about why safety is important. 2) summer drinks with UCL dark and friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>♟️ why i&#39;m considering a PhD</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/%EF%B8%8F-why-im-considering-a-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 16:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/%EF%B8%8F-why-im-considering-a-phd/</guid>
      <description>This is actually a revised copy of something i wrote on March 7th 2021, before i started my PhD. It had two purposes at the time: 1) it clarified my ideas about pursuing a PhD and 2) acted as a manifesto of what i hope to achieve. Now i&amp;rsquo;m coming to the end of it, I feel comfortable with it and think it&amp;rsquo;s a good read. Enjoy.
My current situation&amp;hellip; As of right now my career looks something like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>an argument for prosocial agents</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/an-argument-for-prosocial-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 17:48:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/an-argument-for-prosocial-agents/</guid>
      <description>To build machine-learning systems (agents) that are useful in the real world, they need to be able to cooperate with each other and with humans, not only at deployment but throughout their lifetime. I predicate my research on this and the following beliefs:
Multi-agent deployment: Transformative AI is unlikely to appear in isolation, but will instead be developed by multiple competing actors, giving rise to a large population of capable agents [1, 2].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>history through optimisation</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/history-through-optimisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 17:48:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/history-through-optimisation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction All decision tasks (questions with Yes-No answers) can be framed as optimisation tasks (minimum quantity for Yes), and as such, any problem can be considered the optimisation of some quantity. It&amp;rsquo;s an attractive, though mostly useless framework, as optimisation tasks are much harder to solve. Yet somehow we’re in a position, with advances in machine learning, where we have effective computational methods for optimisation. Thus problems in physics, anthropology and economics can be reframed as optimisations and with enough compute, could be replicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>remembering Big Narstie</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/remembering-big-narstie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 17:38:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/remembering-big-narstie/</guid>
      <description>One of my biggest fears is forgetting things, it&amp;rsquo;s like the beginning of dementia and the loss of self. So when I realise that some of favourite internet moments are being slowly removed, I get unnecessarily stressed.
For example, recently I tried to show my friends Big Narstie on Toddla T&amp;rsquo;s BBC 1Xtra show. We simply could not find it. It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly hilarious and shows the unfiltered Narstie that I&amp;rsquo;ve come to trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lessons from my first job</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/lessons-from-my-first-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 21:35:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/lessons-from-my-first-job/</guid>
      <description>For a couple of my peers and myself, covid-19 has provided a time for some introspection and with that the existential regret that we don’t really know what we’re doing here. 2 years into my career, I’ve decided to consolidate what principles I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt for the next five years.
Be Kinder To People My idea of business has been profoundly influenced by pop culture. From Steve Jobs to Don Draper, those titans of industry showed me that to be successful you have to be mean, ruthless and unforgiving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>golang&#39;s rand and concurrency</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/golangs-rand-and-concurrency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 16:12:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/golangs-rand-and-concurrency/</guid>
      <description>This is a bug I encountered when writing a ray-tracer in Golang and thought it was worth a quick share.
The Idea When rendering an image using a ray-tracer, each pixel value can theoretically be calculated independently, making parallelisation an attractive prospect. When rendering the image, we iterate through each position and call the sample method to calculate RGB value for that pixel:
Go makes running threads (go routines) really simple and so the idea was to split the for loop into separate threads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quantum teleportation 101</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/quantum-teleportation-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 16:12:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/quantum-teleportation-101/</guid>
      <description>Twice in the past week i’ve been asked to explain Quantum Teleportation (QT), firstly at a talk given at a research house and secondly by my tutee. I ended up asking myself plenty of questions as they went by and below wanted to write a concise explanation.
Teleportation Doesn’t Really Mean What You Think Quantum teleportation is a protocol for how we can communicate information with entangled quantum states. It has very little to do with our science fiction idea of teleportation — where matter seemingly hops through space and time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>testing for deep learning</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/testing-for-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 16:12:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/testing-for-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>One of the largest challenges when starting our company was learning how to use deep learning models in production grade software. Whilst we had solved the challenge of proving our models were capable of solving the problem with controlled environment (and nice datasets), building a pipeline and testing suite was difficult and we’d like to share what we’ve learnt.
In particular, our product utilised &amp;ldquo;online learning’’, in which each model is trained specifically for a client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI superpowers (summary)</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/ai-superpowers-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 16:12:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/ai-superpowers-summary/</guid>
      <description>Following on from advice from a flatmate, I’ve decided I’ll be writing summaries of books I’ve just read — hopefully to flush out some of their ideas within my head.
Kai-Fu Lee is someone everyone should know more about. As a PhD student at Carnegie Mellon, Lee created the first speaker-independent continuous speech recognition system. As the second AI winter was settling in, Lee worked at companies such as Microsoft, Apple and even headed up Google China, witnessing the rise of Eastern and Western tech companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>understanding Word2Vec</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/post/understanding-word2vec/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 16:12:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/post/understanding-word2vec/</guid>
      <description>As powerful as computers have become they are still relatively &amp;ldquo;stupid&amp;rdquo;. In fact, computing power normally only tells you how quickly they can perform simple calculations like adding and subtracting. What computers are really bad at is more general abstract questions. That’s stuff like &amp;ldquo;can you notice pedestrians in a photo&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;can you realise how the words &amp;lsquo;king&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;queen&amp;rsquo; are related&amp;rdquo;?
What computers really get is vectors, they love them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>https://akbir.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akbir.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an artificial intelligence (AI) PhD candidate, advised by Tim Rocktäschel and Edward Grefenstette, at the UCL DARK lab.
I&amp;rsquo;m interested in studying techniques to ensure Scalable Oversight. I consider these problems primarily in the setting of multi-agent learning. Our recent work on debate receieved a Best Paper Award 🏆 at ICML 2024.
My research is shaped by my AI safety concerns. I&amp;rsquo;ve developed machine-learning systems at Tractable and Spherical Defence Labs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
